<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-02-07T02:15:49-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Max’s Mind</title><subtitle>Take a dive into Max&apos;s Mind</subtitle><author><name>maxrios</name></author><entry><title type="html">Introducing Moody</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/06/Introducing-Moody/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Moody" /><published>2025-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-02-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/02/06/Introducing-Moody</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/02/06/Introducing-Moody/"><![CDATA[<p>Journaling, or keeping a diary, is a great way to self-reflect. It’s an important part of my life. Over the years I’ve found different ways to journal. I’ve written in notebooks, I’ve written on sticky notes, I’ve written in note apps. It doesn’t really matter where you write, it just matters that you think about what’s trapped in your mind.</p>

<p>In 2024, I was introduced to mood tracking apps. A silly little icon that’s typically linked with a journal entry of how you feel in the moment or the day. My favorite to use was <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.marchlab.haema&amp;hl=en_US">Haema</a>, a minimal-style mood tracking app that had a small feature set. I mostly liked it because of a basic calendar view of all my moods and a really cool widget. After using it for a few weeks, I was disapointed to learn that the payment feature, that allowed you to continue using the app after the free trial, was broken. No more Haema, not more simply designed, worry-free mood tracking. And that was my lightbulb moment. Why not just take all of my favorite features from the mood tracking apps I’ve tried and make one myself? A fun little side project.</p>

<p><em>Spolier Alert: It was not little.</em></p>

<p>Welcome, Moody!</p>

<p>Moody is a diary and mood tracking app I’ve been developing since September of 2024. Its goal is to help people better understand their emotional patterns through simple, daily mood tracking – making self-reflection an accessible and sustainable habit rather than another task on their to-do list.</p>

<p>And to me, everything free is a major cornerstone of this goal. Enjoy all the features without worrying about a price tag.</p>

<p>It’s currently being tested in a closed pilot program on iOS and Android. If you’re interested in trying it out, join the <a href="https://forms.gle/i5y6mFbkiY87zBVF9">early access group</a>!</p>

<p>I plan on writing a bit more about Moody in the future, specifically on my experience using Flutter.</p>

<p>Stay tuned!</p>]]></content><author><name>maxrios</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journaling, or keeping a diary, is a great way to self-reflect. It’s an important part of my life. Over the years I’ve found different ways to journal. I’ve written in notebooks, I’ve written on sticky notes, I’ve written in note apps. It doesn’t really matter where you write, it just matters that you think about what’s trapped in your mind.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/19/Welcome/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome!" /><published>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2025-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/01/19/Welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/01/19/Welcome/"><![CDATA[<p><em>Welcome inside of Max’s mind…</em></p>

<p><br />
A blog / log / notebook / brain dump on tech, video games, books, music, or whatever. Expect a mixed bag of posts that will likely never have a schedule. Some might even just be pictures. The goal is to consolidate my thoughts recorded in far too many notebooks (they’re just so fun to write in) and some Google Docs.</p>

<p>I think a lot goes on in a day, and days are far too long to store everything in your head. As a person with an <em>awful</em> memory, I found these little (occasionally schmedium) notes as a nice reminder of what actually happened. Sometimes a note in a mood tracker might suffice. Sometimes thoughts just need to be forgotten.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I won’t be spending much energy editing these entries. Damare, I apologize in advance. Everyone else, feel free to voice your concerns to the mid-night air – a surprisingly rare occurence.</p>

<p>xoxo</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/dog.png" alt="image" /></p>]]></content><author><name>maxrios</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome inside of Max’s mind…]]></summary></entry></feed>